Spider-Man: Brand New Day is a science fiction, action,
adventure film directed by Destin Daniel Cretton.
The fourth installment in the Spider-Man franchise and part of
Phase Six of the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
Peter Parker / Spider-Man, played by Tom Holland.
Frank Castle / Punisher, played by Jon Bernthal.
MJ, played by Zendaya.
Ned Leeds, played by Jacob Batalon.
Spider-Man: Brand New Day is an upcoming American superhero film based on the Marvel Comics character Spider-Man,
co-produced by Columbia Pictures and Marvel Studios, and distributed by Sony Pictures Releasing.
It is intended to be the 38th film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU) and the fourth film
in the MCU Spider-Man film series following Spider-Man: No Way Home (2021).
The film is being directed by Destin Daniel Cretton from a
screenplay by Chris McKenna and Erik Sommers.
Tom Holland stars as Peter Parker / Spider-Man alongside Zendaya, Jacob Batalon, Sadie Sink, Liza
Colón-Zayas, Jon Bernthal, Mark Ruffalo, Michael Mando, Tramell Tillman, and Marvin Jones III.
Sony was developing a fourth MCU Spider-Man film by
August 2019 alongside No Way Home.
Producer Amy Pascal revealed in November 2021 that it was intended to be the first in a new trilogy
of Holland-led Spider-Man films, with work on the story beginning that December.
McKenna and Sommers returned as writers from the previous films by February 2023, Cretton was
hired to direct by October 2024, and the title was announced in March 2025.
Filming began in August 2025 with location filming in Glasgow, Scotland,
while soundstage work occurred at Pinewood Studios in England.
Additional location work occurred throughout
England, and filming wrapped in December.
Spider-Man: Brand New Day is scheduled to be released in the United
States on July 31, 2026, as part of Phase Six of the MCU.
The film explores themes of secret identity, superhero, based on
comic, super power, marvel cinematic universe (mcu).
The tone is thought_provoking.